Guide to the Robert Richardson Sears Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert Richardson Sears papers
1929-1988
SC0082
Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson)
48.5 Linear feet
These papers document his professional career as teacher and researcher in child psychology. Included are correspondence, memos, research data, manuscripts, course materials, students' papers, grant files, reports, speeches, minutes, and articles. Subjects include his books PATTERNS OF CHILDREARING and IDENTIFICATION IN CHILD REARING; the Kansas City thumb sucking study; research on gifted children; research for a psychological study of Mark Twain; and his affiliations with the American Psychological Association, the Social Science Research Council, the Society for Research in Child Development, and the Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Robert R. Sears, 1970, and the estate of Pauline Sears, 1993.
Gift of Robert R. Sears, 1970, and the estate of Pauline Sears, 1993.
Information about Access
Restricted: for more information contact the University Archivist.
Information about Access
Restricted: for more information contact the University Archivist.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of psychology at Stanford, 1953-1974, and Dean of the School of Humanities and Sciences, 1961-1970, Sears earned his a.b. at Stanford in 1929 and his Ph.D. at Yale in 1932. Before joining the Stanford faculty, he taught at the University of Iowa, where he directed the Child Welfare Research Station, and at Harvard, where he was also director of the Laboratory of Human Development.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of psychology at Stanford, 1953-1974, and Dean of the School of Humanities and Sciences, 1961-1970, Sears earned his a.b. at Stanford in 1929 and his Ph.D. at Yale in 1932. Before joining the Stanford faculty, he taught at the University of Iowa, where he directed the Child Welfare Research Station, and at Harvard, where he was also director of the Laboratory of Human Development.
Description of the Collection
These papers document his professional career as teacher and researcher in child psychology. Included are correspondence, memos, research data, manuscripts, course materials, students' papers, grant files, reports, speeches, minutes, and articles. Subjects include his books PATTERNS OF CHILDREARING and IDENTIFICATION IN CHILD REARING; the Kansas City thumb sucking study; research on gifted children; research for a psychological study of Mark Twain; and his affiliations with the American Psychological Association, the Social Science Research Council, the Society for Research in Child Development, and the Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences.
Description of the Collection
These papers document his professional career as teacher and researcher in child psychology. Included are correspondence, memos, research data, manuscripts, course materials, students' papers, grant files, reports, speeches, minutes, and articles. Subjects include his books PATTERNS OF CHILDREARING and IDENTIFICATION IN CHILD REARING; the Kansas City thumb sucking study; research on gifted children; research for a psychological study of Mark Twain; and his affiliations with the American Psychological Association, the Social Science Research Council, the Society for Research in Child Development, and the Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences.
Access Terms
American Psychological Association.; Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (Stanford, Calif.).; Harvard University --Faculty.; Harvard University. Laboratory of Human Development.; Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson); Social Science Research Council (U.S.).; Society for Research in Child Development.; Stanford University. Department of Psychology.; Stanford University. Department of Psychology.; University of Iowa. Child Welfare Research Station.; Walker, Eleanor; Walker, Eleanor; Child rearing.; College teachers.; Interviews.; Notes.; Psychology.; Speeches.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Original interviews with Kansas City Thumb Sucking study, 1944-1949 (Box 1)
    - Ackers, Donna (Box 1)
    - Alexander, Stephen (Box 1)
    - Allen, Geraldine (Box 1)
    - Baker, Susan (Box 1)
    - Beeman, Daniel (Box 1)
    - Beynon, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Black, Diana (Box 1)
    - Blanch, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Bowser, Johnny (Box 1)
    - Boyle, Judy (Box 1)
    - Brown, Barbara J. (Box 1)
    - Butterworth, Carlyl (Box 1)
    - Chumlea, Ann (Box 1)
    - Coard, Suzanne (Box 1)
    - Colson, Katherine Sue (Box 1)
    - Compton, (John) Douglas (Box 1)
    - Conboy, Carol (Box 1)
    - Cooper, Edward (Box 1)
    - Cunningham, Linda (Box 1)
    - Deets, Patricia (Box 1)
    - Drozda, Kathleen (Box 1)
    - Elben, David (Box 1)
    - Eckerberg, Ann (Box 1)
    - Eisberg, Patty (Box 1)
    - Epperson, Gerald (Box 1)
    - Erwin, Sharon (Box 1)
    - Fleming, Allen (Box 1)
    - Ford, Karen (Box 1)
    - Frazier, Stephen (Box 1)
    - Fredeen, David (Box 1)
    - Fredeen, Martha (Box 1)
    - Fredeen, Susan Ann (Box 1)
    - Gaston, Larry (Box 1)
    - Glen, Dianne (Box 1)
    - Hall, Bill (Box 1)
    - Hallier, Richard (Box 1)
    - Hamilton, Tom R. (Box 1)
    - Harrison, Mary (Box 1)
    - Heckman, Ann (Box 1)
    - Hedge, Johnny (Box 1)
    - Heydt, Tom (Box 1)
    - Hibbard, Michael (Box 1)
    - Hodges, Virginia (Box 1)
    - Holmes, Judy (Box 1)
    - Housh, Roy D. (Box 1)
    - Hover, David (Box 1)
    - Jacobee, Virginia Lee (Box 1)
    - Jacobus, Stephen (Box 1)
    - Jeffries, Sue (Box 1)
    - Jenkins, Edna (Box 1)
    - Jones, Dennis (Box 1)
    - Keller, Kathy (Box 1)
    - Kiley, Mary (Box 1)
    - Kranz, Linda (Box 1)
    - Kuder, Susan (Box 1)
    - Lawrence, Jerry Ann (Box 1)
    - Lawrence, Katherine (Box 1)
    - Layne, Shirley (Box 1)
    - Lewis, Maurine (Box 1)
    - Majors, Mary Kay (Box 1)
    - Medill, Robert (Box 1)
    - Morgan, Suzy (Box 1)
    - Parr, Jimmy (Box 1)
    - Partin, Nancy (Box 1)
    - Robinson, David (Box 1)
    - Sanders, George (Box 1)
    - Schmeltz, Karen (Box 1)
    - Schmeltz, Paul (Box 1)
    - Sexton, Michael (Box 1)
    - Sheldon, Earl (Box 1)
    - Shirley, Stephen (Box 1)
    - Shoemaker, Dennis (Box 1)
    - Six, Carol (Box 1)
    - Spellman, Jonathan (Box 1)
    - Taylor, Joan (Box 1)
    - Turner, Jackie (Box 1)
    - Stewart, Frank (Box 1)
    - Warren, Ann (Box 1)
    - Watt, Charles (Box 1)
    - Weatherby, Nancy (Box 1)
    - Wolff, Carol (Box 1)
    - Wuertz, Peter (Box 1)
    - Yager, Charles (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous committees (Box 1)
    - CCI Committee on Community Interrelations (Box 1)
    - Iowa Mental Health Hygiene Society (Box 1)
    - Clinical Psychology, Journal of, 1946-1948 (Box 1)
    - Clinical Phsychology, Journal of, 1944-1948 (Box 1)
    - Midwestern Pyschology Association (Box 1)
    - Iowa Psychological Association (Box 1)
    - Applied Anthropology, Society for (Box 1)
    - American Association of University Professors (Box 1)
    - "Sky King", 1946 (Box 1)
    - National Safety Council (Box 1)
    - Clinical inquiries, 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - Occupied Europe project (Box 1)
    - U. S. Public Health Service, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    - Speeches, 1942-1943 (Box 1)
    - Speeches, etc., 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - Inter-University Collaboration Committee (Box 1)
    - New applications, Veterans Administration training program for clinical psychologists, 1946 Fall (Box 2)
    - VA accreditation (Box 2)
    - Children's Bureau, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
    - NRC Council on division of anthropology and psychology, 1945-1948 (Box 2)
    - Society for Research in Child Development (SRCD) agenda, 1946 (Box 2)
    - NRC - Committee on Child Development SRCD (Box 2)
    - NRC - Committee on Child Development, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
    - NRC - Joint Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
    - NRC - clinical psychology - Surgeon General, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
    - Army Committee - clinical psychology (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council Old Age Committee, 1946-1948 (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council Grants-in-Aid Committee, 1945 (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council Grants-in-Aid Committee, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council Grants-in-Aid Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
    - American Psychology Association (APA) material (Box 2)
      - Committee on Ethics (Hobbs) (Box 2)
      - Division of Personality and Social Psychology, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
      - Division of Personality and Social Psychology, 1946-1949 (Box 2)
      - Board of Directors, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
      - Board of Directors, 1946-1947 (Box 2)
      - Board of Directors, 1947-1948 (Box 2)
      - Board of Directors, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
      - Executive Secretary, 1945-1946 (Box 2)
      - Executive Secretary, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
      - Division on childhood adolescence (Box 2)
      - Division on childhood adolescence, 1946-1949 (Box 2)
      - Committee on Publicity and Public Relations, 1944-1945 (Box 3)
      - Committee on Publicity and Public Relations, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
      - Policy and planning board, 1945-1946 (Box 3)
      - Policy and planning board, 1946-1947 (Box 3)
      - Policy and planning board, 1947-1948 (Box 3)
      - Policy and planning board agenda, 1948 (Box 3)
      - Policy and planning board, 1948-1949 (Box 3)
      - Committee on Graduate Training, 1945-1946 (Box 4)
      - Committee on Graduate Training, 1946-1947 (Box 4)
  - Patterns of Child Rearing by Sears, Maccoby and Levin. Published in 1957 by Row, Peterson & Co. (Box 5)
    - Chapter 1 - drafts, etc. (Box 5)
    - Chapter 1 - final (Box 5)
    - Chapter 2 - infant care (Box 5)
    - Chapter 3 - feeding (Box 5)
    - Chapter 4 - toilet training (Box 5)
    - Chapter 5 - dependency (rough manuscript) (Box 5)
    - Chapter 5 - dependency (Box 5)
    - Chapter 6 - sex (Box 5)
    - Chapter 7 - aggression (Box 6)
    - Aggression excerpts (Box 6)
    - Chapter 8 - discipline (Box 6)
    - Chapter 8 - first draft (Box 6)
    - Chapter 9 - techniques of training (Box 6)
    - Chapter 10 - the development of conscience (Box 6)
    - Chapter 11 - sexes and ordinal position (Box 6)
    - Chapter 12 - economic level, education, and age of the parents (Box 6)
    - Chapter 14 - conclusions (Box 7)
    - Correspondence (includes permissions), 1954-1958 (Box 7)
    - Bronfenbrenner's comments (reader) (Box 7)
    - Iowa conference, 1957 November 22 (Box 7)
    - Publishers (Box 7)
    - Reviews (Box 7)
  - Identification in Child Rearing by Sears, Rau and Alpert. Published in 1965 by Stanford University Press., 1964-1965 (Box 8)
    - Second reader (Box 8)
    - Preface, Chapter 1, Chapter 2 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 3, Chapter 4 (Box 8)
    - Chapter 5, Chapter 6, Chapter 7 (Box 8)
    - Appendices, References (Box 8)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1986-046
  - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Search for Feminist Studies/Psychology faculty, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Envelope titled: IBM totals - work sheets for the various chapters (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Envelope titled: summary of statistics for analysis of variance, Chapters 5-9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Envelope titled: verbatim recording of interviews and preliminary scoring (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tabulated scores for IBM (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Raw data for research thesis R001: "Attitudes of Children Toward Authority as Projected in their Dollplay at Two Age Levels" Elizabeth Johnson, 1950; Two volumes not in labeled folder (Box 2)
  - Envelope titled: work sheets for analysis of variance (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Attachment, dependency and frustration, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Personality development (Psych 112), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rosen - research fund for APF (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ahmad correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Psych 133 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - SRCD (Society for Research in Child Development) - business material (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SRCD - editorial (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - SRCD - general (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - SRCD - proposal to Grant Foundation (Sapir) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - SRCD - correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - SRCD - correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - SRCD - material from former SCRD President (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Papers from Psych 133, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Ryder, R., "C.S. Lewis" (2 copies), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Haney, J., "George Eliot", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Huntsberger, S., "O. Henry", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hubbard, J., "Edgar Allen Poe", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Klein, S., "Sigmund Freud" (2 copies), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Keat, R., "Checkjov", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Ghilarducci, V., "Charlotte Bronte", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Frederick, H., "Kafka", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ahearne, J., "Herman Hesse", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Collins, R., "Strindberg", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Schmidt, J., "D. H. Lawrence", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Swain, L., "D. H. Lawrence", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Hill, S., "Arthur Conan Doyle", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Becker, H., "Louisa May Alcott", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Lapidus, D., "Hemingway", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Annual faculty report (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - AAAS symposium - Bernard Weiner (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - SRCD dittoes, Attachment, Dependency and Frustration, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - SRCD dittoes (revised), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Reviews - Contemporary Psychology (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Faculty meeting minutes (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Psych 133 - booklet on program in student evaluation of teaching and courses (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - G. Stanley Hall Award committee, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Human biology correspondence (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Human subjects research (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "A Planning Proposal for Research in Emotional Growth and Mental Health" (bound volume) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Permission to use RRS material (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - "Dean Sears - filing", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Graduation ceremony speech, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Pre-Hullian Hull (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Attachment and dependency papers (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Marquis, D. G. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "After Great Pain" review manuscript (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Episodic analysis manuscript (two folders) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Bowlby's Separation - review, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Weiner book chapter (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - MT speech - Montreal, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - SRCD President, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Ancients Revisited - final draft, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Paper, "Relation of Early Socialization to Self-Concepts and Gender Roles in Middle Childhood", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - RRS autobiography (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - SSRC Committee on gifted children, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - SSRC Committee on Gifted Children meeting, 1976 October 22-24 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - History article, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Newton follow-up "self esteem" (Box 4)
    - Letter re draft (Box 4)
    - "Rules of correspondence" between "sets" of data and printout (Box 4)
    - Content of results, sets 1-10 (Box 4)
    - Printout (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence undated, circa 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence (alphabatized by name, chronologically) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Washington NIH trip, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - University Lecture committee (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Note on measurement of gender roles, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - George Washington University correspondence (conference on early childhood), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Professorial appointments, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Psych 194E, Life History, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - International Pyschohistorical Association, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Interoffice memos, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Journal of Pyschohistory (History of Childhood Quarterly), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Ketch. conference, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - President's file SRCD, 1973 December (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - The multiple department concept, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Permissions, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Psychology library, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Patterns, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Sear's work, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Modern thought conference, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Meetings - Research in Childhood Development, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - The role of expectancy in adaptation to aging (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Seven Ages of Man manuscript (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Speeches (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - SRCD summer materials, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Forms of behavior related to perceptiual response in infancy, Part 1 & 2 (Richard Meili) (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Psychology of biography, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - "Executive Competence in Toddlers" (Charles Wenar) (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - SRCD reviews and materials, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - SRCD symposium, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Targets (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - National Science Foundation, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - NHPRC (National Historical Publications and Records Commission) - archives funding (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - NHPRC - planning (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - NHPRC - Spencer Foundation (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - NHPRC - NEH I (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - NHPRC - NEH II (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - NHPRC - Application Phase II (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - NHPRC - Johnson and Johnson (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Cravens (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Archives, technical - data archives problem (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - correspondence (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - Summer, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - preservation project (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - committee, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - Lynn Bonfield (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - 4th annual report (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - committee, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - committee, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - committee, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Archives Committee/SRCD Council - committee, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - SImple play technique (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Dependency (categories and bibliography); aggression bibliopgraphy (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Research planning (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hypnosis (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Social class, culture type (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Whiting (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Card sorting; success and failure (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Seminar on personality, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Social theory (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1949-1963 (Box 7)
    - Ammons, Robert B. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bach, George R. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Baldwin, Alfred L. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Beller, Emanuel K. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Bishop, Barbara Merrill (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Broderick, Arthur J. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Buxton, Claude (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Conference (alumni) and outside speeches (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Chasdi, Eleanor Hollenberg (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Faigin, Helen (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Freud, Anna (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Gewirtz, Jack (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Himmelweit, Hilde T. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Hovland (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Hunt, J. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Laboratory of Human Development (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Levin, Harry (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Luma, A. R. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Lesky, Ruth Wilson (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - McCandless, Boyd R. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - McClelland, David C. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - McKee, John (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Mental Health Survey (Western states) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Miller, Daniel R. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Mussen, Paul H. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Publishers (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Richard, Geraldine (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Schlorberg, Harold (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Shipton, James M. (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Skard, Ase Grude (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Southwest study (Eleanor Hollenberg Chasdi) (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Speech notes (R. R. Sears) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Board of Syndics, Harvard University Press, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Academic personnel recommendations (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Alumni committee (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Committee on rehabilitation (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Child development (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Child development curriculum (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Child center (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Land and building development (advisory committee) (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Reprint and mailing list (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Invitations (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Sociology (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - President's office (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Sterling, J. E. Wallace (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Ford Foundation and CASBS (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Center for advanced study in behavioral science (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - American Child Guidance Foundation (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - American Parents Committee (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - American Psychology Association (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - APA - Executive Secretary (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - APA - Division 7 developmental (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - APA - Division 8 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Foundations' fund for research in psychology (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - British Psychological Society (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - California State Psychological Association (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Rockerfeller Foundation (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Society for Research in Child Development (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - USPHS Training Committee (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - VA Area Psychology Advisory Council (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital, Palo Alto (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Dissertation material - Bee, Helen (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Correspondence - A (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence - B (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Special files and correspondence (Box 8)
    - C (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Comp. Developmental Behavior (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - California State Psychology Association (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - D (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - E (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Experimental Psychologis, Society of (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Encyclopedia of the social sciences (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - F (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - G (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - H (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hawaii State Hospital (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - I (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - J (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - K (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - L (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Mc (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - M (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Milwaukee project (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - N (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - O (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - P (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Palfrey House (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Potential personnel (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Psychology department (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Q (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - R (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - S (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Stolz project (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Singer (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - T (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - USPHS project (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - U (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - V (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - W (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - XYZ (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, A-B, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, C-B, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 37)